wohoops.com 2011-06-24

# Charity Fundraising through Personal Web Pages – Your Cause

|  |  |   
---|---|---  
| 

|  | Privacy Policy and Terms of Use  
---|---  
  
This Privacy Policy covers the Web site [www.YourCause.com](http://www.yourcause.com/).  
---  
**Our Commitment to Privacy**  
YourCause.com is committed to safeguarding your privacy online and has prepared this Privacy Policy to describe our collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information through the online community Web site, [www.YourCause.com](http://www.yourcause.com/) (the “Community”).  
**Information Collected**  
We automatically track and collect the following information (“Standard Web Traffic Information”) when you visit our Web site: your IP address, domain server, type of computer, and type of web browser. This information assists us in administering our Web site and diagnosing problems, and in improving your experience in our Community.

We also use “Cookies” (described below) to save your password so you do not have to reenter it each time you visit our Web site.

For you to access certain services offered through the Community, we require you to become a member of our Community by providing us with your name, email address, zip code, sex, date of birth and country (“Contact Information”). At your discretion, you may provide us with personal information in addition to your basic Contact Information.

If you post information on any of our blogs, testimonials, forums, message boards, or any other input method we provide, such information you provide may be available to other members of the Community and other Web site visitors.

If you create your own Cause Page, you may elect either a Basic Service Account, at no charge, or a Premium Service Account for a monthly fee. If you elect a Premium Service Account, we collect additional information consisting of your credit or debit card details, including a card type, a card number and an expiration date (“Credit Card Information”).

If you make an online donation, we collect Credit Card Information from you.  
  
**Information Use**  
YourCause.com will make your Contact Information available to the credit card authorization company when necessary to process a donation made by you to your chosen charity. In addition, we will make your Contact Information available to the charity or charities to which you have made donations. We also make your information available to the fundraiser who's Cause Page you have contributed through. When you make a donation to a Cause Page, your name will appear publicly on that page.

We do not share your Credit Card Information. We do not retain your Credit Card Information, except to process payments for Premium Services.

Please note that if you are creating your own Cause Page, we will pass on your name, address and email address to your chosen charity for administrative purposes. Your information may also be made available to the charity’s agent or third-party event organizer specified by your charity. 

When we pass along your Contact Information to charities, YourCause.com cannot control how charities use this information. If you prefer not to receive future communications from the charity (other than any acknowledgment the charity may provide of your donation), please contact the charity directly.

We send emails to the address you provide, including but not limited to confirmation emails, messages from members, and newsletters. We will not share your email address with third parties, except where noted above. 

We may share aggregate Standard Web Traffic Information (such as statistical, demographic and IP information) with third parties, however, this information does not include your Contact Information.  
  
**Tell a Friend**  
If a member elects to use our “Tell a Friend” function, we ask them for the friend’s email address and automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the Cause Page specified by the member. This information is stored temporarily for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.  
**Confidentiality and Security of Contact Information**  
Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your Contact Information with third parties, unless such disclosure is necessary (as determined in our sole discretion) to comply with a court order or other legal process or protect the rights or property of YourCause.com or its affiliates.

Although YourCause.com uses reasonable measures to maintain the security of your Contact Information, no company, organization, or online community, including YourCause.com, can fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information.  
  
**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small text file that a Web site places on a site visitor’s computer hard drive. Its purpose is to let the site know when a user visits and to perform certain functions such as saving passwords and personal preferences.

Cookies help evaluate visitors’ use of a Web site, such as what viewers want to see and what they never read. This information allows YourCause.com to better focus online information and to concentrate on information people are using.

Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. If you would like to turn this feature off, you will need to change the settings of your Internet browser.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our Web site and other Web sites. In the course of serving advertisements, these companies may place or recognize a unique 'cookie' on your hard drive, and may use information about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to measure advertising effectiveness and to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.  
  
**Accessing and Updating Contact Information**  
To ensure that all of your Contact Information is correct and up to date, you may visit your personal profile to review and update your Contact Information that we have already collected.  
**Other Disclosures**  
We may share some or all of your Contact Information with our Affiliates, in which case we will require our affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.  
**Canceling Your Cause Page**  
You may cancel your Cause Page at any time by sending a cancellation request to Accounts[at]yourcause.com. If you choose to do this, please know that any information you have already provided will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  
**Links to other Web sites**  
Our Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by the YourCause.com Web site. Our Web site may contain links to other Web sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects your information.  
**Other Limits to Your Privacy**  
We also make blogs, testimonials, forums, and message boards available to you on our Web site. Any information you disclose in these areas becomes public information. Because we have no control over the use of information you disclose in these areas, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information. Any information you disclose on our Web site may be available to other members and available on third-party Web sites. Accordingly, such information is not subject to this Privacy Policy.  
**Business Transactions**  
If YourCause.com goes through a business transaction, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or a sale of all or a portion of its assets, your information may be among the assets transferred. If any such transaction results in any change to this Privacy Policy, YourCause.com will notify visitors, members and donors by means of an update to this Privacy Policy.  
**Acceptance of Our Privacy Policy**  
Your use of the YourCause.com Web site indicates your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any aspect of this policy, you should immediately discontinue your use of the YourCause.com Web site and the services offered on the Web site.

YourCause.com may change, modify or update this policy from time to time, without advance notice, by posting such changes, modifications or updates on the Web site. You are deemed to have accepted the then current version each time you use our Web site or one of our services, so please check back periodically.  
  
**How to Contact Us**  
Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please email us at Accounts[@]yourcause.com.  
**Terms of Use**  
A cause must directly support an official, **IRS–registered, 501(c) (3), tax-exempt organization**. Unfortunately, we cannot accept causes for individual needs or private purposes due to IRS regulations. 

You understand and agree that the Company may, but is not obligated to, review the Site and may delete or remove (without notice) any Site Content or User Content in its sole discretion, for any reason or no reason, including User Content that in the sole judgment of the Company violates this Agreement or which might be offensive, illegal, or that might violate the rights, harm, or threaten the safety of users or others. 

In addition, we reserve the right to reject any cause or user content for any reason including, but are not limited to, content that we deem obscene, pornographic or sexually explicit, depicts graphic or gratuitous violence, makes threats of any kind or that intimidates, harasses, or bullies anyone, or is derogatory, demeaning, malicious, defamatory, abusive, offensive or hateful. 

This Site is intended solely for users who are thirteen (13) years of age or older, or under 13 only with parental consent. Any registration by, use of or access to the Site by anyone under 13, is unauthorized, unlicensed and in violation of these Terms of Use. By using the Service or the Site, you represent and warrant that you are 13 or older and that you agree to and to abide by all of the terms and conditions of this Agreement.  
  
|  |   
  
|
